Why does the government take your guys and send them to
Зачем власть берёт ваших парней
die in the war? And they
отправляет погибнуть на войну да А
bring others from other countries so that they can
других с других стран привозит чтобы они
live and
уже тут жили и
work here. Oh, hello guys,
работали О здравствуйте пацаны Здорово
great, great. What are you talking about and about everything, for
здорово О чём общаетесь да по всём
example,
например
well, as long as it’s not this, don’t call names, talk
ну лишь бы не это не обзываться говорить
about the substance,
по существу
don’t give questions to the point  right away Come on
не давайте вопросы по существу сразу
What are the goals of the special military
Давай Какие цели специальной военной
operation
операции
? Well, we didn’t set the goals. That is, you don’t
Ну это не мы цели ставили То есть вы не
know why you are being sent to
знаете За что вас отправляют
die, I’m sending you for Russia. Well, what for
умирать направляю за Россию Ну а в чём
Russia? You lived in Russia, you spent a lot of
за Россию Вот вы жили в России куча
money on your education there,
бабок тратили на своё образование там
medicine there, sports, and now a lot  grandmothers
медицину там спорт а теперь куча бабок
go to war, what’s the trick? Well, the trick is not
уходит на войну в чём фишка Ну фишка не
in us, but they just send us and we go
в нас а нас просто отправляют и мы идём
like this and you guys are not like that with us. It’s clear. We do
так и вас реб не так у нас Понятно Мы за
n’t come for our land, ladies, someone else’s country is
свою землю дамы не приходим чужу стра
our country. Yes, it was attacked.
вот наша страна Да на неё напали А вас
Why are they taking you away?  they explain that
че вот вас забирают объясняют ти что
you need to go to a foreign country in the World
тебе надо пойти в чужую страну в ЧМ
Cup, it’s a joke. Well, look, I’ll explain to you, I don’t
прикол Ну вот смотри я тебе объясн я не
mean that I support the policy of our
то что поддерживаю политику нашего
state, but they’ve been pouring into our ears there for 8
государства но нам вот льют в уши там 8
years. I have a hard time doing this. Sometimes you have to
лет Я с трудом это ве Иногда приходится
believe
верить
it,
ю
it’s not very easy for you. Look.  You saw
вам не вот очень просто Смотри Ты видел
Donetsk, like they were bombing Donbass for 8 years
Донецк вроде говоря 8 лет бомбили
and Donetsk just stood there and
Донбасс а Донецк как стоял так и стоит а
what they did with the bakhmut and solida, they
что сделали с бахмутом и солида в ноль
killed it, yours already in solidarity, the resident
его убили ваши уже го в солидарен житель
remained like some kind of homeless
остался вроде какой-то
person, or look at
бомж не то смотрите
all the cities there that were occupied by
все города там которые были оккупированы
Russia  since the year Donets Lugansk They stood
Росси е с года Донец Луганск Они стояли
and
и
stand wore to zero there was nothing
стоят носил под ноль ничего не было
like that Yes, that is, it turns out they decided
такого Да а то есть получается решили
to protect the Donbass and killed hundreds of thousands of
защитить Донбасс и убили сотни тысяч
people what’s funny about the Donbass themselves,
людей в чём прикол причём самих донбасов
that is, look people lived in Bakhmut and in
то есть смотри люди жили в бахмуте и в
solidarity they say the dudes now we
солидарен говорят чуваки сейчас мы
will come to you  liberate or slaughter their city, what’s the
придём вас освобождать или шили их город
joke, where are we from? We know, we
прикол да мы откуда Знаем мы же мы там
weren’t there, we don’t know, we ourselves want to
не были знает Мы не знаем мы сами хотим
talk to you so that someone there can
с вами поговорить чтобы кто-то там
tell us what they
рассказал что
understand, and they pay for the dead of
почём понял а выплачивают за погибших
these Russians, they pay
этих россиян выплачивают родственникам
some
какую-то
amount to their relatives Yes  they pay out, but we don’t know
сумму Да выплачивают только не знаем
what amount was paid for the killed, but
какую а выпла сумму за убитую а
pay out is there someone I know
выплачивать выпла А есть кто-то из
who has already been buried? Well, we haven’t heard
знакомых кого уже закопали Ну не слышали
yet, but there is a lot in the Kaluga region. Well, it
мы пока но по Калужской области много
doesn’t say that, you
есть Есть Ну что не говорит что ну
know, well, there is, and what is there, women,
знаешь Ну есть есть а что там женщины
women?  are they rebelling a little or not No, what? Well,
женщины бунтуют немножко или нет Нет а
first of all, this is an isolated case of
Ну во-первых это единичный случай чтобы
someone being brought to the area where
кого-то привезли дерев там на район
10 people stole a planting with flags, don’t look if you
10 украла засе флагами не смотри ты если
look like that Look, for example, look
смотри так Посмотри например посмотри
Here in the cemetery in the fireplace Where you have
Вот в кладбище в костраме Где у вас
this airborne regiment, everything is there  [ __ ] on the bottom
десантный этот полк там всё сра по подли
Why is
у Почему
there a lot of everyone who was a military man or died in the war
много все кто военный или погиб на войне
Yes, everyone was buried with a flag Absolutely Yes and
Да всех хоронили с флагом Абсолютно Да и
For example, in my city there is an alley
Например у меня в городе вот есть аллея
we walk every day we see everyone who
мы идём каждый день мы видим каждого
died, what is the problem with us no one
погибшего в чём проблема у нас никто это
hides it, the thing is A  you’ll just
не прячет дело в том А у вас их как раз
melt them away, like hide them somewhere so
растают типа ховають типа чтобы где-то
that people don’t see how many of you
прятать чтобы люди не видели сколько вас
died So yes, no, well, you know,
сдохло Так что да да нет ну вот знаешь т
we have a lot of guys with mobile phones
у нас много ребят мобили
Zro Well, there’s no such thing as a large-scale
Зро Ну нет такого чтобы масштабно пр
transport of coffins, [ __ ] there, they were transported, they were transported, Well
везли гробы бля там везли везли везли Ну
yes, I was
да быва
from the regional
ра с областного
center from the regional
центра с областного
center, I understood Well, just at the dacha there, well,
центра понял Ну просто на даче там ну
somehow I know we communicate with each other and
как-то знаю общаемся между собой а
look, I If I’m not mistaken, I see that the
смотри я Если не ошибаюсь Я смотрю что
Kaluga region, in my opinion, is the Leader in the
Калужская область по-моему Лидер по
number of migrants
количеству мигрантов
Yes, well, there is, yes, it
Да ну ну есть
turns out sri  I don’t understand
есть да то получается сри Я не понимаю
if there aren’t enough workers in Russia, then
если в России не хватает рабочих рук то
why does the government Bert send your guys to
зачем власть Берт ваших парней
die in the war? And they bring others from
отправляет погиб на войну да А других с
other countries to
других стран привозят чтобы они уже тут
live and work here, so we all ask the same
жили и работали так вот мы тот же самый
question.
вопрос задаём
Why is it that a person doesn’t want to
все Почему так который человек не хочет
go?  they pay him money for the war and
идти на войну ему платят деньги и
which person wants to go and he wants They
который человек хочет пойти и он хочет
don’t
Денег их не
take the money I’m not talking about that a little bit, not for the
берут Я я немножко не о том говорю не на
war I mean that for example, here
войну Я имею в виду что например вот у
you have migrants coming to work there as
вас приезжают мигранты работать там
taxi drivers, there are different ones there, yes, that is,
таксистами там ещё разными да то есть
Why for you  there is no this
Почему для вас нету этой
rapa T already a narrow
рапе Т уже узкая
specialty you
специальность буровые
can’t take drilling masters the person thought
мастера не возьмёшь человек соображал
more or less
более-менее
migrants won’t come to us in a
мигрант к нам никак не подтянутся в
taxi Yes, they are everywhere and you Have us
такси Да они везде и у вас У нас
for you speak so badly about them
за вы так про них говорите
What’s bad is
плохо Что плохо есть
why are they the same people as you  they’re just
Поче они такие же люди как и вы просто
driving you like cattle to die in Ukraine,
вас гонят как скот умирать в Украину
like on the contrary, they’re bringing them to live
типа А их наоборот привозят чтобы жили
in your place, you’re also being driven to
на ваших местах вас тоже гонит
die. Wait, look, we’re on our land for you. Look, they’re
умира Подожди смотри мы на своей земле
taking people from the Kaluga
вас Смотри у вас берут людей с Калужской
region, throwing them into Ukraine, they’re dying,
области бросают в Украину они умирают
people are dying, less labor is needed and they’re
людей стат меньше нужно рабочие руки и
bringing  from Tajikistan, for example, yes
привозят с Таджикистана например
no, look, the police passed through here
да нет вот смотри у нас вот прошла
last year, they passed through
милиция в том году она прошла один раз у
you once there, I didn’t just guys didn’t pass through
вас там я не просто ребят не прошла у
you once, look at you. Look, you
вас один раз смотри у вас Смотри ва вас
were deceived that they passed through once, you
обманули что она прошла один раз у вас
haven’t finished mobilizing the decree
не закончилась мобилизация указа про
there is no talk about the end of mobilization because
окончание мобилизации нету потому что у
you have had a permanent mobilization for a year and it
вас год идёт мобилизация перманентная ни
doesn’t affect anyone, that’s how it all ended
никого не трогает вот Как закончился всё
that year, not a single person, only the
в том году ни одного человека только
Volunteers, I’m sure I’ll tell you how
Добровольцев уверен я тебе расскажу как
those Volunteers look at the Zolkin channel, yes,
те Добровольцы вон посмотри канал золкин
for example, the cops, in short,
есть да например менты короче типу
throw something in and  They say this now,
подкидывают что-то и говорят так сейчас
either you sit down or write like you’re a
или сядешь или пиши типа что ты
volunteer,
доброволец идёшь Повер
look like that, I’m telling you, go to the
так вон смотри я тебе говорю зайди канал
Zolkin channel, you know, Vladimir Zolkin
золкин знаешь вот Владимир золкин с
communicates with
пленными общается
Russian prisoners, it’s just space. Well, we live in
российскими просто космос Ну мы живём в
this country. Well, there’s not a single friend
этой стране Ну нет ни одного знакомого
who’s [ __ ] under anyone there.  they threw in the rowing,
чтобы кого-то там [__] под гребли
believe me, please, by
подкинули вот поверь пожалуйста а кстати
the way, look, I still can’t understand it,
Смотри вот я не могу ещё понять вот смо
I see you don’t live very richly,
я вижу вы так не совсем богато живёте да
yes Well, if Russia is such a country with
Ну вот если Россия Такая страна с
Don’t like
Не ну в
commanders Well, yes, the city also
командиров Ну да гостиницу тоже квартиру
rented a hotel like this for itself Yes,
такую себе сняли
look, it just turns out that
горо Да смотри просто получается что
Russia is such a rich country with diamonds,
Россия такая богатая страна с алмазами
oil and gas, but where does all this
нефтью газом Да куда это всё
go? Well, this is
девается Ну
not a market, but they take it all away from you, they steal it,
не тобто от вас это всё забирают воруют
and in short, they put it on their
И короче себе на
yachts. Well, like you, you
яхты Ну как и у вас у вас там тоже не
have no less there, so look at us there in
меньше нет так смотри у нас там в
America, with us  We fight with them instead
Америке у нас Мы боремся с ними вместо
of fighting with them
того чтобы с ними бороться
Kochet surrender in ukra you died
[__] сда в укра вы умер
who no one demands anything or rather it
кто никто ничего не требует вернее
depends on us they told us like this
зависит от нас нам сказали вот так вот
we are such simple people That is you In short
мы такие простые люди То есть вы Короче
nothing depends on you in your country
от вас в вашей стране ничего не зависит
at all  there was mobilization people didn’t
именно даже мобилизация была люди не
want to go you consider yourself
захотели пойти вы считаете себя
Rami you consider yourself
Рами вы считаете себя
slaves I personally no nya So wait If
рабами Я лично нет ня Так подожди Если
you are not slaves Yes so it depends on you what
вы не рабы Да так что от вас зависит что
you decide in your country I
вы решаете в своей стране я
decide family My children my wife I love them that’s what
решаю семья Мои дети жена я их люблю вот
next
что ре а что дальше
Putin I live for my
Путин Я живу для своей
family and not for Putin Okay, I’ll run, let’s go
семьи а не для Путина Хорошо побегу
ahead, T right away, he’s just as
давай най T прямо зараз он
polite
важливо